<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xml:lang="en">
<title>Install and Use BAM Bootloader for MPC55xx on Phytec phyCORE-MPC5554</title>
<sect1>
<title>License</title>

<para>Author: Jan Kobler, Kobler Systems GmbH, email: eng1@koblersystems.de</para>
<para>This work (text) by <ulink url="http://www.koblersystems.de">Kobler Systems GmbH</ulink> is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License. To view a copy of this license, visit <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"/>.</para>
<para></para>
</sect1>
<sect1>
<title>Install Python</title>

<para>Follow the instructions on <ulink url="https://www.python.org"/> to install Python. For <code>mpc55xx-bam-loader-g1</code> select the latest stable version of <emphasis role="strong">Python 3</emphasis>. At the moment this is Python 3.4. </para>
<para>If <code>pip</code> is not already installed follow the instructions on <ulink url="https://pip.pypa.io/en/latest/installing.html"/></para>
</sect1>
<sect1>
<title>Install the software</title>

<para>Use the tool <code>pip</code> to install the package <code>mpc55xx-bam-loader-g1</code></para>
<screen>
pip install mpc55xx-bam-loader-g1</screen>

<para>You can find more information about using <code>pip</code> on <ulink url="https://pip.pypa.io/en/latest/user_guide.html"/>. </para>
<para>If not yet installed, the software <code>pyserial</code> will be also installed. You can find more information about pyserial on <ulink url="http://pythonhosted.org/pyserial"/>. </para>
<para>Test if the application is started. On the command line type: </para>
<screen>
mpc55xx-bam-loader</screen>

<para>A help text should appear with a list of possible arguments. </para>
</sect1>
<sect1>
<title>Test with Phytec phyCORE-MPC5554</title>

<para>You need to set the Jumper JP1 to the memory, which has been erased. When BAM cannot start an application in the selected memory, then it listens on the eSCI_A and on the CAN port. </para>
<para>Connect the serial cable to the lower serial port. </para>
</sect1>
</article>
